{
    "data" : [
        {
            "question": "Who is the father of C language?",
            "a": "Steve Jobs",
            "b": "James Gosling",
            "c": "Dennis Ritchie",
            "d": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
            "correct": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a valid C variable name?",
            "a": "int number",
            "b": "float rate",
            "c": "int variable_count",
            "d": "int $main",
            "correct": "d"
        },
        {
            "question": "All keywords in C are in ____",
            "a": "LowerCase letters ",
            "b": "UpperCase letters",
            "c": "CamelCase letters",
            "d": "None of the mentioned",
            "correct": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which of the following is true for variable names in C?",
            "a": "They can contain alphanumeric characters as well as special characters ",
            "b": "It is not an error to declare a variable to be one of the keywords(like goto, static)",
            "c": "Variable names cannot start with a digit ",
            "d": "Variable can be of any length",
            "correct": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is valid C expression?",
            "a": "int my_num = 100,000 ",
            "b": " int my_num = 100000",
            "c": " int my num = 1000",
            "d": " int $my_num = 10000",
            "correct": "b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cannot be a variable name in C?",
            "a": "volatile",
            "b": "true",
            "c": "friend",
            "d": "export",
            "correct": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is short int in C programming?",
            "a": " The basic data type of C",
            "b": " Qualifier",
            "c": " Short is the qualifier and int is the basic data type",
            "d": "All of the mentioned",
            "correct": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which of the following declaration is not supported by C language?",
            "a": "String str",
            "b": "char *str",
            "c": "float str = 3e2",
            "d": "Both String str; & float str = 3e2",
            "correct": "a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which keyword is used to prevent any changes in the variable within a C program?",
            "a": " immutable",
            "b": "mutable",
            "c": "const",
            "d": "volatile",
            "correct": "c"
        },
        {
            "question": " What is the result of logical or relational expression in C?",
            "a": "True or False",
            "b": "0 or 1",
            "c": " 0 if an expression is false and any positive number if an expression is true",
            "d": "None of the mentioned",
            "correct": "b"
        }
    ]
  }